MEMORIES OF THE ALHAMBRA
Episode 14
Translated by
Hyun-Joo Choi at Netflix
Ripped and synced by
gabbyu's subs
Okay.
Have the next outfit ready.
This is so annoying.
-When is this going to end?
-I have an announcement.
-Hey, look.
-I am the detective in charge of the case.
About ten minutes ago,
-the respondent told
-Did he show up?
that he cannot attend the questioning.
What? What kind of trick
is he trying to pull?
He probably got scared and didn't show up.
We'll tell you more
about the investigation later on.
Hold on.
Get off me.
Have you looked into it?
It looks like Jin-woo met
with Cha Byeong-jun this morning.
There are a lot of witnesses who saw him
at Cha Byeong-jun's lecture hall.
But why? Why did they meet?
How would I know?
Things seem to be unfolding
in an unexpected way.
Something doesn't feel right.
The number you have dialed is unavailable.
Please leave a message after the beep.
CHA BYEONG-JUN
The number you have dialed is unavailable.
Is he not picking up?
What's going on?
Why is he ignoring my calls?
Did Jin-woo fool us again or what?
CHA BYEONG-JUN
What are these bastards up to?
Hey.
Did you talk to the lawyer?
How ridiculous...
He told you not to attend
the witness interview tomorrow.
Why?
Apparently, something's come up.
He didn't give me a reason.
He said you should just wait.
Cha Byeong-jun told him to tell us that.
We've been fooled, completely.
I told you something didn't seem right.
You hung up
when he didn't tell you anything?
You moron, what the hell do you even do?
Bitch, why are you taking it out on me?
Listen, you bitch.
You're the one who met up with
Cha Byeong-jun.
You met with him of your own accord
and cut a deal with him.
I warned you not to trust that old geezer.
I wondered why he wanted
to join hands with us out of the blue.
I bet he had already cut a deal
with Yoo Jin-woo.
He just used us to threaten him
and ditched us. Do you understand?
I told you not to use
that stupid head of yours.
You brought all this upon yourself, okay?
How dare you take it out on me?
God damn it, this is so frustrating.
I'll kill them.
Kill who?
I'll kill them all.
All right.
Kill them or not,
do whatever you want.
Where are you going?
I asked you where you're going!
Shall I really kill them all?
Hello.
Aren't you Go Yu-ra by any chance?
To Central Police Station, please.
Oh, that's Go Yu-ra!
Get her on the camera!
It's Go Yu-ra.
Yu-ra, please say a few words.
-You're not scheduled to be here today.
-Did it get rescheduled again?
-Why did Mr. Yoo cancel the questioning?
-Why are you here?
Please say a few words.
What brings you here?
Yu-ra.
-Look over here!
-Say a few words!