So, what do you think?
Wow.
It's for you, right?
It's for both of us.
Don't go away.
Don't worry.
There's no enough blood
left in my legs to go anywhere.
( phone ringing )
CHARLIE ( on machine ):
Hey, it's Charlie.
Do your thing
when you hear the beep.
( beeps )
WOMAN:
Listen, you lousy SOB.
I will not be treated like this.
Either you call me or you are
going to be very, very sorry.
I love you, Monkey Man.
Charlie?
Who is that?
Damn telemarketers.
A telemarketer
who calls you "Monkey Man."
I'm on some weird list.
Okay, it's a woman
I went out with once,
and she got a little clingy.
You are a bad, bad boy.
And yet, you're always
the one getting spanked.
( phone rings )
Geez.
CHARLIE ( on machine ):
Hey, it's Charlie.
Do your thing
when you hear the beep.
( beeps )
MAN:
Uh, Charlie, it-it's Alan,
uh, your brother.
No big deal.
Uh, just wanted to touch base.
My-my wife threw me out
and I'm kind of losing
the will to live.
So, when you get a chance,
I'd really love to,
oh, I don't know...
Hey, Alan,
I'm sorry to hear about that.
Uh, so, where are you
going to go, to a hotel?
Wow.
Huh?
Well, yeah, I-I guess
you could... stay here.
Okay.
I'll see you
when you get here.
We better hurry.
Oh, is she staying over?
'Cause I may have parked
behind her.
* Men, men, men, men,
manly men *
Twelve years
and-and she just throws me out.
I mean, what was
the point of our
wedding vows?
You know,
"Till death do us part."
Who died? Not me, not her.
How did you get in my house?
Okay, Charlie, the key
in the fake rock only works
if it's among other rocks.
Not-not sitting on
your welcome mat.
Excuse me,
but if you put the fake rock
in with a bunch of other rocks,
it's impossible to find
when you're drunk.
You know, I'm
a good husband.
I-I'm faithful.
Is she?
Is she what?
Faithful.
( scoffing )
Don't be ridiculous.
I mean,
Judith doesn't even like sex.
I mean, all she kept saying
was she feels suffocated,
you know.
She kept going on and on,
"I'm suffocating.
I'm suffocating."
What does that mean?
Has a women ever said that
to you?
Well, yeah...
but not a woman who
doesn't like sex.
And-And Jake.
Jake?
My son.
Oh, yeah, teenagers are pretty
sophisticated these days.
He's ten.
WOMAN:
Charlie,
I'm going to go.
CHARLIE:
Oh, no.
You two need to talk.
I'll call you tomorrow.
I'm sorry to hear
about you and your wife.
Oh, come on, you leaving
isn't going to bring them
back together again.
Look, okay, this is just
until things settle out.
A couple of days max.
She will come to her senses.
Yeah, that's what women do.
Look,
you can have the guest room.
I'll grab some sheets.
That's okay.
I brought my own.
Brought your own sheets?
I like my sheets.
Okay, then, good night.
No, no, wait, wait.
Charlie, I mean,
we hardly ever
talk to each other.
( sighs ):
What do you want
to talk about, Alan?
I don't know. Uh...
I was named
Chiropractor of the Year
by the San Fernando Valley
Chiropractic Association.
Okay, then, good night.
No...
No, Charlie, Charlie,
what about you?
What's, uh, what's
going on with you?
Well, Alan,
there's not much to say.
I make a lot of money
for doing very little work.
I sleep with beautiful women
who don't ask about my feelings.
I drive a Jag,
I live at the beach,
and sometimes,
in the middle of the day,
for no reason at all,
I like to make myself
a big pitcher of margaritas,
take a nap out on the sundeck.
Huh.
Okay, then, good
night, Charlie.
Good night.
Good night, Monkey Man.
Boy, is your eye red.
You should see it from in here.
What are
you doing here, Jake?
My mom brought me.
Will you take me
swimming in the ocean?
( sighs ):
Can we talk about it
after my head stops exploding?
Why is your head exploding?
Well, I drank a little
too much wine last night.
If it makes you feel bad,
why do you drink it?
Nobody likes
a wiseass, Jake.
You have to put a dollar
in the swear jar.
You said "ass."
Tell you what...
here's 20.
That should cover
me till lunch.
Now, what I think
you need to do
is to make a list.
On one side, put
what you don't like
about our marriage,
and on the other
side, what you do.
Alan, sometimes when I think
about coming home to you,
I start crying in my car.
Okay, that would probably
go on the "don't" side.
Why would I lie?
The ocean is closed today.
For God's sake, Charlie,
do you think you could put
some pants on?
Look at me, Judy.
I could barely make it
down the stairs.
Uh, Charlie, could
you and Jake, uh...
Yeah. Come on, kid.
We'll have breakfast
out on the deck.
I already had breakfast.
Okay, we'll have lunch.
Not lunchtime.
( imitates explosion )
That's his head exploding.
Judith, I-I can change.
Oh, please, Alan.
You are the most rigid,
inflexible, obsessive,
anal-retentive man
I've ever met.
Rigid and inflexible?
Don't you think that's
a little... redundant?
My mom and dad are splitting up.
Yeah, looks that way.
You're lucky.
When I was your age,
Your mom is my grandma.
Yup.
Grandma says
you're a bitter disappointment.
Hey, sport.
Uh, your mom wants
to say good-bye.
Uh, listen,
he doesn't know anything
about what's going on
so let's just keep this
to ourselves.
Our little secret.
Wh-Why is she saying
good-bye to him?
Oh, well, she's going
to be spending the weekend
with her sister... in Vegas.
uh, so, we decided
that Jake would stay with me.
With you?
Well, with us.
I'm hungry.
Is this going
to be a problem?
I guess not.
Thanks.
Oh, uh, hey, listen.
I've got to call
my office.
Would you mind
making him lunch?
Sure.
Thanks.
What are you smiling about?
You don't have any food.
Yeah, but I'm not the one
who's hungry.
Who's smiling now, shorty?
CHARLIE:
You drink milk?
Just with cereal.
Okay.
Not that milk.
That milk.
What's the difference?
That's DairyFarm.
We drink DairyBarn.
Fine.
Happy?
Why would I be happy?
It's just milk.
Cute.
Keep it up,
you'll be on one of the cartons.
Okay, cereal.
We got Lucky Charms,
Cocoa Puffs,
Frosted Flakes,
Maple Loops...
I want Maple Loops.
* It's got oats and corns
and wheat *
* It's the sweetest
breakfast treat *
BOTH:
* It's maple, maple,
ma... ple-icious! *
You know who wrote that song?
Your Uncle Charlie wrote that.
No lie?
Kid, if I was going to lie,
I'd say I wrote
"Stairway to Heaven"
not "The Maple Loop Song."
You two
are really good together.
Thank you.
So, does your wife sing, too?
Oh, uh, no.
I'm not married.
Oh. What a shame.
Wow...
you're even better
than a dog.
Dr. Bloom. Yes, yes.
This is, uh, Alan Harper.
Yes. My wife and I need
to cancel our marriage
counseling appointment
for this afternoon.
Yes, well, well,
something came up.
Well, it's-it's-it's
kind of personal.
I mean, I-I-I...
Well, yeah, I know the
point of these things is...
I've got to go.
Um, hello?
Is Charlie home?
Uh, uh, no. I'm, uh,
I'm Charlie's brother.
Can I, uh, can
I help you?
Oh, hi, Charlie's brother.
I'm Rose.
I'm Charlie's housekeeper.
So you're-you're
a housekeeper?
Well, housekeeper, slash,
actress, slash, hand model.
( laughs )
I just do this
to keep the wolf from the door.
( roars )
( laughs )
You know what I mean?
Sure. Sure, come on in. Uh...
Oh.
Yeah, I can smell him.
Smell who?
Your brother.
He has a very musky scent.
Uh-huh.
Well, I'll just, uh...
let you get to work.
Oh, wait.
Oh, no. It's okay.
* It's got oats
and corns and wheat *
* It's the sweetest
breakfast treat *
* It's maple, maple, maa....
Jake, buddy,
take a break.
ALAN:
What, uh...
What took you so long?
We stopped for ice cream
'cause I'm a babe magnet.
I got to take a squirt.
Why do you assume
he learned that from me?
Because I learned it from you.
Hey, thanks for cleaning up.
Oh, it wasn't me.
Rose was here.
Rose?
You let Rose into my house?
She said she was your maid.
What the hell.
She glued the damned cabinets
shut again.
Again? You've got somebody
who comes in regularly
to glue your cabinets?
Oh, you've met some
of the whack jobs
I've gone out with.
It's not that big a stretch.
Oh, oh. So this is my fault.
Who let her in?
Oh, you are a deeply
disturbed man.
Oh, I'm deeply disturbed?
Who showed up here in
the middle of the night
with his own sheets?
Hey, at least I care
what I sleep on,
or should I say,
who I sleep on.
Hey, pal, of
the two of us,
I'll bet I'm
the only one
who slept with a
married woman recently.
EVELYN:
And isn't that something
to brag about?
( thudding )
Hi, Mom.
EVELYN:
Do you have any idea
how hurtful it is
to hear about
your own son's divorce
on the street?
What divorce?
Wh-what street?
How did you get in my house?
You stay out of this.
I'm here to help your brother
through a very difficult time.
How could you do this to me?
Do what?
Now when I want
to see my grandson,
I am going to have
to make an appointment
with Judith,
who-- let's face it--
was never very warm to me.
And what if
there's another man there,
shacking up with her?
Have you even stopped
to consider that?
I think he's considering it
now, Mom.
Here's your
iced tea, Grandma.
Oh, thank you,
my little angel.
Oh, darling, I asked
for a lemon wedge.
All right, here's what
you're going to do.
You and Jake will come live
with me.
After all, I'm just
rattling around
in that big house all by myself.
Mom, that's very considerate,
but as soon
as Judith and I work things out,
I'm going to be back
at my own house.
Oh, sweetheart, grow up.
Think about
what I said.
You're my son, and I'll always
have room for you in my house
and in my heart.
I-I love you, too, Mom.
I love you, too, Mom.
Too little. Too late.
So, Vegas was good?
It was fine.
Alan, I really
want to apologize
for putting you
through this.
I was wrong to blame you
for my unhappiness.
No. No need
to apologize.
What's important is
that we're here,
and we're working
on our marriage.
You look great,
by the way.
Must be all the
extra oxygen they pump
into the casinos.
Alan...
And-and-and-and
you were right.
I-I see now that the time apart
did us both a lot of good.
I know I've grown.
I am not that suffocating guy
you threw out of the house
four and half days ago.
Let me tell you that.
Alan...
And Jake's doing fine.
I know you were concerned
about him
being around my brother,
but it turns out
Charlie's great with kids.
All right, last card,
down and dirty.
Kings bet.
Dollar.
I'm in.
In.
I'll see the dollar
and raise it five.
You raised $5 on that?
I call.
Call.
Queens full of nines.
( groans )
Hey, kid, don't you know
what a full house is?
Yeah, and I also know
what a psych-out is.
CHARLIE:
I love this boy.
And-and-and I think
that we're going
to look back on this
as-as a new beginning
for our marriage,
a rebirth, a Renaissance,
if you will.
Alan, I think I'm gay.
All right.
We'll make a list.
On one side,
we'll put gay stuff...
I'll see you...
and raise you 20.
I think he's got you, pal.
He's bluffing.
He always pulls his ear
when he bluffs.
How about it, Mighty Mouse?
You in?
Take him down.
Call you.
I hate this kid.
What the hell is going on here?
You said "hell."
Throw a dollar in the pot.
What?
Hey, we all had to.
Charlie, may I speak with you
privately, please?
Whose deal is it?
ALAN:
Jake, go to bed!
I'm out.
What is wrong with you?
Are you insane?
Do you have any sense
of right and wrong?
Probably not. How was dinner?
How could you put Jake
in a poker game
with grown men?
I obviously can't be trusted.
So, how was dinner?
I leave you
alone with him
for a couple of hours.
I mean, it's just...
I'm just going
to keep asking, Alan.
Dinner was swell.
We both had the veal piccata,
and she's gay.
Wow.
Most chicks won't eat veal.
Why do I even try
talking to you?
Oh, come on.
I'm just trying to get you
to lighten up a little.
I don't need
to lighten up.
The world I
live in is dark.
Dark and rainy.
And you're
useless in it.
Oh, really?
I wasn't useless
when you needed a place to stay.
Well, obviously,
that was a mistake.
Are you sure?
Maybe we should make a list.
( playing soft blues on piano )
Uncle Charlie?
What's going on?
Can't sleep?
No.
My dad says we're moving
to Grandma's tomorrow.
Yeah. That'd keep me up.
You know, if it makes
you feel any better,
you won 80 bucks
in that last hand.
85.
80. House gets a cut.
I wish my dad was as cool
as you.
Hey, don't sell
your dad short.
He loves you more than
anything in the world.
You know that,
don't you?
I guess.
How come
you don't have any kids?
I don't know.
Maybe because I love me
more than anything in the
world.
Uncle Charlie?
Yeah?
I don't want to go to Grandma's.
I'd rather stay here.
Yeah, well, your dad knows
what's best for you.
Okay.
Good night, Uncle Charlie.
I love you.
Yeah.
Okay.
( kissing )
You got to love
a kid like that.
I even played him
"Stairway to Heaven,"
and he still liked the
Maple Loops song better.
Oh. Charlie,
I haven't seen you
in two weeks.
Now, do you want to talk
about your nephew,
or do you want to have sex?
Oh, sex.
Definitely sex.
Let me ask you
something.
Yeah?
Do you ever think
about having kids?
Whoa, Charlie,
we got a good thing going.
Can't we just leave it at that?
What are you doing?
I thought we were going
to have sex.
How am I supposed to have sex
while your biological clock
is going off?
( phone rings )
Hey, it's Charlie.
Do your thing
when you hear the beep.
( beep )
ROSE:
Hi, Monkey Man.
I was just thinking
about you
and wondering
why we hurt each other so much.
Rose, it's me,
Monkey Man.
Charlie?
Yeah. Hey, listen,
let me ask you a question.
Is there something
inherently wrong
with asking a woman
you're involved with
if she wants kids?
Oh, Charlie.
We got a good thing going.
Why do you want to mess it up?
( line disconnects )
Look at you.
All grown up
and back living
with Mom.
How good do you feel
about yourself right now?
On a scale of one to two.
I'm not back living with Mom.
I'm simply staying here
till Judith and I
work things out.
So... one?
What do you want, Charlie?
Well, I figured you been
here a couple of weeks.
You got to have blood
in your stool by now.
So I thought if you and
Jake wanted to come back
to my place for a while,
that that'd be okay.
Wait a minute. Are you saying
you want me to come back
and live with you?
Well, truthfully, no.
I want Jake to come back
and live with me,
but I figure,
you're a package deal.
Thanks, but we're doing
just fine here with Mom.
Oh, come on, Alan.
We can't let Jake
be exposed to her
on any kind of
ongoing basis.
There's no ongoing basis.
He's only here on weekends.
That's too much.
Piranhas can strip
an entire cow in an hour.
Alan, we've got to get him
away from her.
I mean, look what happened
to us.
And what happened to you?
Hi, Mom.
Charlie, you're a grown man.
Perhaps it's time
to stop blaming your mother
for your own shortcomings.
Alan, the divan
is not for sitting.
Charlie,
get off the couch.
Uncle Charlie!
Oh, there's my
good boy.
And what did
I tell you
about yelling
in the house?
Grandma, I'm suffocating.
( laughs )
Sound familiar?
You're right.
This madness must end.
Here, I got you
your own key.
* Men.
I am not comfortable with this.
I mean, maybe I should go
wait in the car.
You're not waiting
in the car.
Trust me. This is a
great way to meet women.
I don't want to meet women.
I'm still married.
Oh, come on.
You're wife's out
meeting chicks.
Why shouldn't you?
* It's got oats
and corn and wheat *
* It's the sweetest
breakfast treat *
* It's maple, maple,
ma... ple-icious! *
Your son is just adorable.
Oh, thank you.
You and your...
life partner must be so proud.
You're right.
Go wait in the car.